<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: octopress | HuongNguyen's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://zhuongnx.github.io/blog/categories/octopress/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://zhuongnx.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-06-10T15:20:11+07:00</updated>
  <id>http://zhuongnx.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Hướng Nguyễn]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Plugins]]></title>
    <link href="http://zhuongnx.github.io/blog/2015/06/10/plugins/"/>
    <updated>2015-06-10T13:43:11+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://zhuongnx.github.io/blog/2015/06/10/plugins</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There are other plugins for octopress, but here&rsquo;s an overview of the ones you&rsquo;ll be likely to use while blogging. This is mainly a description and demo, so be sure to follow the links beneath each section for examples and documentation.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>Excerpts</h2>

<p>When writing a post, you can add an HTML comment <code>&lt;!--more--&gt;</code> to split the post for an excerpt. Only the first section of the post, before the comment, will show up on the blog index.</p>

<h2>HTML5 Video Tag</h2>

<p>This plugin makes it easy to insert mp4 encoded HTML5 videos in a post. Octopress ships with javascripts which detect mp4 video support (<a href="http://modernizr.com/">using Modernizr</a>) and automatically offer a flash player fallback.</p>

<p><a href="http://octopress.org/docs/plugins/video-tag/">Examples &amp; documentation »</a></p>

<h2>Image Tag</h2>

<p>This plugin makes it easy to insert images in a post, with optional class names, alt and title attributes.</p>

<p><a href="http://octopress.org/docs/plugins/image-tag/">Examples &amp; documentation »</a></p>

<h2>Block quote</h2>

<blockquote><p>Give a man a fish, he&rsquo;ll have food for a day. Teach a man to fish, and he&rsquo;ll always come to you with his fishing problems.</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Blogging Basics]]></title>
    <link href="http://zhuongnx.github.io/blog/2015/06/10/blogging-basics/"/>
    <updated>2015-06-10T13:11:58+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://zhuongnx.github.io/blog/2015/06/10/blogging-basics</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Octopress offers some rake tasks to create post and pages preloaded with metadata and according to Jekyll&rsquo;s naming conventions.
It also generates a global and a category based feed for your posts (You can find them in <code>atom.xml</code> and <code>blog/categories/&lt;category&gt;/atom.xml</code>)</p>

<p>If you are using zsh in the command line, then please add <code>alias rake=noglob rake</code> to your zsh config to prevent the <code>zsh: no matches found</code> error that occurs when running these rake tasks.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>Blog Posts</h2>

<p>Blog posts must be stored in the <code>source/_posts</code> directory and named according to Jekyll&rsquo;s naming conventions: <code>YYYY-MM-DD-post-title.markdown</code>
The name of the file will be used as the url slug, and the date helps with file distinction and determines the sorting order for post loops.</p>

<p>Octopress provides a rake task to create new blog posts with the right naming conventions, with sensible yaml metadata.</p>

<h3>Syntax</h3>

<pre><code class="sh">rake new_post["title"]
</code></pre>

<p><code>new_post</code> expects a naturally written title and strips out undesirable url characters when creating the filename. The default file extension for new posts is <code>markdown</code> but you can configure that in the <code>Rakefile</code>.</p>

<h3>Example</h3>

<pre><code class="sh">rake new_post["Blogging basics"]
# Creates source/_posts/2015-06-10-blogging-basics.markdown
</code></pre>

<p>The filename will determine your url.
With the default permalink settings the url would be something like <code>http://site.com/blog/2015/06/10/blogging-basics/</code></p>

<p>Open a post in a text editor and you&rsquo;ll see a block of yaml front matter which tells Jekyll how to processes posts and pages.</p>

<pre><code class="sh">---
layout: post
title: "Zombie Ninjas Attack: A survivor's retrospective"
date: 2011-07-03 5:59
comments: true
external-url:
categories:
---
</code></pre>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
